(upbeat music)
- Hello English learners,
welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today, we're bringing you a lesson
that was requested by one of our listeners.
- Yes, that's right.
We got a request for a
dialogue about a receptionist.
- So a receptionist at
an office or at a hotel.
So today's dialogue is simple,
but we're gonna be looking
at some really great phrases.
- Yeah, phrases that will help you sound
really, really professional
and really fluent.
- So we are at an office
today, and the receptionist
is greeting somebody
that has an appointment.
- All right, let's see what happens.
(upbeat music)
Good afternoon, may I help you?
- Yes, I'm here to see Joanna Stevens.
I have an appointment at four.
- Certainly, may I take your name?
I'll let her know you've arrived.
- Sure, it's Josh O'Neill.
Miss Stevens will be with you momentarily.
Can I offer you something to drink?
- Yes, coffee would be nice, thank you.
Here you are.
Miss Stevens is ready for you now.
I'll show you to her office right this way.
Just watch her step here.
(screaming)
(upbeat music)
- Well, that's pretty embarrassing, hey?
- That was embarrassing.
That's what happens to women
when they wear high heels, see?
- Actually, that happened
to me last weekend.
- Really?
- I fell down the stairs and
my knees are quite blue.
(laughing)
- Oh, now see, high heels are dangerous.
I don't know why women wear them.
- Well, I don't know, but that's
not what we're here to discover.
- Right, okay, so let's take a look at
some of these great
phrases in fluency builder.
- Fluency builder.
- Well, I really liked
how this receptionist
used some excellent phrases
to sound really professional.
And one thing she said
was, certainly, certainly.
So why did she say certainly?
- Well, this is a nice way to respond.
Do you make the other person know
that you understand what they said?
- So, Josh O'Neill said,
"Yes, I'm here to see you,
Joanna Stevens, I have
an appointment at four.
" - Certainly.
- So she is saying, "I
understand what you said.
" - Yes.
- And then she said,
"May I take your name?
" - May I take your name?
- May I take your name?
" - So this is a nice way of
saying, "What is your name?
" - Yeah.
- So, now this is really important
because if you said, "What is your name?
" Is that correct?
- It's correct, but it's not really very...
- Exactly, or I would say
polite to a certain extent.
- Yes.
- Okay, so may I take your name?
- May I take your name?
- You use this phrase when you are
going to write down the person's name.
- Right, so if you meet
somebody on the street or at a bar,
you wouldn't say,
"May I take your name?
" - No.
- Unless you're going to write it down.
- So usually for an office setting where
the receptionist has to write down the name?
- Yes.
- All right, one more phrase.
Ms. Stevens will be with you momentarily.
- Okay, Ms.
Stevens will be with you momentarily.
- Will be with you momentarily.
- Okay, so this is really polite.
- Yes.
- Momentarily, what does that mean?
- In a moment.
- So, again, she
could have said, "Ms.
Stevens will come
out soon, or Ms.
Stevens will see
you in a minute.
" - Yes.
- But that's, again, it's
not really that polite, right?
- Yeah, so when you want to be formal,
you can say, "Ms. Stevens
will be with you momentarily.
" - Okay, that's a
really nice phrase.
- All right, there's so
much in this dialogue,
so many great,
wonderful, polite phrases.
So why don't we listen to it one
more time, but this time, slow down.
(upbeat music)
- Good afternoon, may I help you?
- Yes, I'm here to see Joanna Stevens.
I have an appointment at four.
- Certainly, may I take your name?
I'll let her know you've arrived.
- Sure, it's Josh O'Neill.
- Ms. Stevens will be with you momentarily.
Can I offer you something to drink?
- Yes, coffee would be nice.
Thank you.
- Here you are.
Ms. Stevens is ready for you now.
I'll show you to her
office, right this way.
Just watch your step here.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, so it's pretty
clear now, but there's still
a couple of phrases that
I would like to look at.
So why don't we look
at the last two sentences?
Okay, Ms. Stevens is ready for you now.
Ms. Stevens is ready for you now.
- Ms. Stevens is ready for you.
So when she says ready for
you, what does that mean?
- Prepared to speak to you.
- Okay, so instead of saying
Ms. Stevens is ready or Ms.
Stevens can see you now, you use
this great little phrase is ready for you.
- Okay, and then she said,
I'll show you to her office.
- I'll show you to her office.
- This is a lovely way of saying
I will take you to the office.
- I'll take you to the office.
- And she followed it
by saying right this way.
- Right this way. - Right this way.
- So again, walk this way.
- Walk this way, this way please.
- Yes, right this way.
- It sounds really, really nice.
- Really polite, really welcoming.
- Right, and especially if
you use it together, right?
I'll show you to her office
right this way, please.
- Yes.
- Okay, so it's a really great way of
being polite to somebody at an office.
- Now the final useful
phrase, watch your step.
- Watch your step.
- So watch your step.
You see that everywhere in the signs.
- Be careful.
- Be careful where you step.
- Yes, be careful where you're walking.
- Okay, so obviously she didn't
watch her step and she felt, she felt.
- Okay, so really great phrases.
Let's listen to this
dialogue one last time.
(upbeat music)
- Good afternoon.
May I help you?
- Yes, I'm here to see Joanna Stevens.
I have an appointment at four.
Certainly, may I take your name?
I'll let her know you've arrived.
- Sure, it's Josh Bonil.
Miss Stevens will be with you momentarily.
Can I offer you something to drink?
- Yes, coffee would be nice, thank you.
- Here you are.
Miss Stevens is ready for you now.
I'll show you to her
office, right this way.
Just watch your step here.
(screaming)
(upbeat music)
- All right, so a really simple dialogue,
but with a lot of good phrases in there.
And it's also a good review for
more advanced students, right?
- Yeah, remember like these
phrases can really help you sound
more professional, more
welcoming, more polite, basically.
- Okay, so if you have
any questions or doubts,
please come to our
website, englishpot.com.
- And Marco and I are always around to
respond to your questions and comments.
- Okay guys, so we'll see you there.
And until next time, it's goodbye.
- Bye.
(upbeat music)